Gahan Saraiya

I am Firmware Development Engineer working at Intel Technology India Pvt Ltd. having 5+ years of experience with excellent skill and understanding of workflow and architecture of Python, UEFI Firmware, DevOps. I also like to contribute in open source too and spreading the knowledge (#philanthropist for knowledge!). Interested to work in Architecture design of Optimized Quantum Computing Algorithms for Multiprogramming and DevOps.



Experience

Jun 2020 -Present

Silicon Firmware Development Engineer

Intel Technology India Pvt. Ltd.

Foundation Framework Development for edk2 platform automation and validation Managing end-to-end Software Development Life Cycle including licensing, legals and IP Planning, and various applicable Security and static code analysis. Managing automated testing of functional validation of Firmware with TeamCity, Jenkins and artifact publishing on Artifactory, and publishing webhooks on JIRA

Jun 2019 -May 2020

Silicon Firmware Development Engineer Intern

Intel Technology India Pvt. Ltd.

BIOS Firmware Development for Client products with the framework EDK2, UEFI Firmware, Involvement with assessing new debugging solutions and OpenBoard Package

Jul 2017 -Apr 2018

Software Developer

Quixom Technology

SaaS-Employee management system (chat, surveys, benchmark, analytics...) and Restful API Development; socket programming in python to receive continuous data from IoT device and display chunks of data meaningfully, web portal for rendering dynamic menu content in Kodi

2015 -2017

Freelance

Designer

Web Scraping, Designing of banner, memento and certificates



Education

Jul 2018 -M.Tech Computer Science and Engineering, Institute of Jun 2020

Technology, Nirma University

PPI: 8.49

Aug 2013 -Apr 2017

B.E. Computer Engineering, GTU

CGPA - 8.08

Jun 2011 -Mar 2013

12th Science, GSHSEB

74.92 %

Jun 2010 -

10th, GSHSEB

Mar 2011



Achievements and Extra Curriculum Activity

Firmware Configuration Presentation at UEFI Developers Conference & Plugfest

2019-Present

2023

4000+ reputation on Stackoverflow

2017-Present

Active volunteer on Peer Learning, Cultural and team building activity

2018

Rank #1 for Python challenges on hackerrank

2018

Rank #112 from 2lacs+ participants in Techgig's National Coding Contest 2018

2018 2017

Pluralsight IQ 248 out of 300 for Python

2016

Google Admin system Administration for Institute

2015

Zonal Winner in Cyber Security arranged by Braintech 2017

Catch Him If You Can - Ethical hacking workshop by Ankit Fadia

2014

Technical Event and Placement Coordinator

2014

Establishment of complete network for Department



Address

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

E-mail

gahansaraiya@gmail.com

Date of birth

September 09, 1995

Website

gahan9.github.io

GitHub

github.com/gahan9

gahan9.medium.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/gahan-saraiya

Twitter

twitter.com/mark gahan



Skills

Languages - Python, C, Rust, Shell Scripting, SQL, LaTeX, YAML

Frameworks - Edk2, Django, PyCUDA, Pandas, Tkinter, Selenium, Octave

Tools and Services - GitHub Actions. Restful APIs, JFrog Artifactory, Teamcity, JIRA, Puppet, Docker, Docker Compose, Jenkins, AWS, GiT, Prezi



Languages

English

Hindi

Guiarati



2020 -Present

2018

Firmware Automation Framework

Description: Lead SDL for an automation foundation framework for high scaled volume of silicon devices with edk2 UEFI firmware;

- seamless configuration of system without any manual intervention for BIOS configuration.
- · SDL activities like legal compliance, security, licensing, static code analysis
- · Continuous deployment and test with jenkins and tox configurations
- · Release Artifact management to JFrog Artifactory using GitHub Actions
- https://github.com/intel/xml-cli

Consummating Research Projects using Agile Manifesto

Description: Utilization of Agile Manifesto for consummating research projects. Enlightening the appropriateness of Scrum for the research projects which is a widely used agile manifesto at present in the software industry.

Inventory Management and GST Billing for Mobile Shop
Full stack Developer

Description: To avoid the headache of manual billing automated GST billing system designed to manage stocks and update according to purchase and sales and generate GST invoice for sales.

2017-2018

Streaming Box

Full stack Developer

Description: An alternate streaming service to DTH and providing easy customized IPTV streaming service based on Kodi (formerly xbmc) Framework

- Backend Streaming Service, authentication and server security with Django Framework and REST API
- Web Portal to enable vendor customize Streaming Front-end UI for their users
- Cross compilation and Native compilation to enable various platform support as Android, Windows and MacOS



Area of Interest

- Quantum Computing
- DevOps



Interests

- Piano
- Chess
- Gaming
- Workout
- Singing & Music



Publications

2016

A Review on Honeypot: Track the Attack. NCCICT, 2016